本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：想名字好难   木浅   martin008  杨一勾
翻译：hh  杨爱菜  某羽  校对：油炸电风扇  小酸奶  杨一勾
时间轴：avis  壬虚浪影  Spohy
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十三集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你以为我不知道
You think that I don't know that
只要我告诉他们这是哈维做的
all your problems are solved
你就万事大吉了
if I tell them that Harvey did this?
如果说我没想过迈克应该做个交易
I would be lying if I said it didn't cross my mind
那我一定是在说谎
that maybe Mike should think about making a deal.
现在他们抓走了你爸爸
And now that they've taken in your father,
别告诉我你没有过同样的想法
you can't tell me that the thought hasn't crossed yours too.
想过和说出来可不是一回事
Thinking about it and talking about it aren't the same thing.
我接到一个电话  是一篇关于
I got a call about an article
迈克・罗斯如何飞速蹿升到初级合伙人的文章
on Mike Ross' meteoric rise to junior partner.
问题是哈佛没有迈克・罗斯这个人
The problem is there is no Mike Ross.
你匿名举报了这件事
You reported it anonymously,
因为你不想做坏人
because you didn't want to look bad.
我之所以匿名举报
I reported it anonymously
是因为我为自己任上发生这种事而感到羞愧
because I was ashamed that it happened on my watch.
我那么爱你
I loved you,
你却让这种愚蠢的秘密成为我们之间的绊脚石
and you let some stupid secret come between us
只因为你无法信任我
because you couldn't trust me with it.
只要你承认自己犯下的错
All you have to do is admit what you did,
这些就会随之而去
and all of this goes away.
希拉站出来了
Sheila came forward.
她承认是她写的邮件
She admitted she was the one who wrote the e-mail.
你和你的合伙人被传讯
You and your partners are hereby subpoenaed
提供律所所有文件
to hand over every single document in the entire firm.
哈维  我觉得这不是个好主意
Harvey, I'm not sure this is the best idea.
我们得知道她手里有什么  这有什么坏处吗
We need to know what she has. What's the downside?
坏处就是就是我们要进入庭审了
The downside is that we move up the trial.
迈克  不管我们愿不愿意  庭审总会来的
Mike, this trial's coming, whether we like it or not.
我们越早知道她的计划
And the more time we have knowing her game plan,
对我们越有利
the better off we'll be.
-完蛋了  -怎么了
- Holy shit. - What?
我之前替这家伙考过法学院入学考试
I took the LASTs with this guy.
那又怎样
So what?
那他就能给吉布斯提供
So he can give Gibbs something
关于我的新证据了
she doesn't even have on me yet.
可如果这么做  他的职业生涯就毁于一旦了
Yes, but to do that, he'd be ruining his whole career.
也就是说  即使他还记得你
Which means, even if he remembers you,
比起你怕他  他更怕你
he's more afraid of you than you are of him.
所以别瞎紧张了
So calm the hell down.
好了  我们速战速决
All right, let's make this quick.
法官大人  速战速决
Your Honor, making it quick is exactly
也是我们的请求
what we're asking you to do.
她还没递交她的证据
She hasn't handed over her discovery yet.
我还在整理案卷
I'm still building a case,
而且庭审日期还未确定
and we haven't even set a date for the trial yet.
人们不想完成任务时
And the check's in the mail, and all the other things
就会说正在准备之类的话
people say when they don't wanna do what they have to do.
我的任务是保护公众
What I have to do is protect the public
免遭你这类人的毒害
from the likes of you.
好了  你们够了
All right, that's enough.
罗尔斯法官
今天把证据给他们
Get that discovery to them by the end of the day.
既然如此  我方要求
In that case, we'd like to ask that the day of the trial
在两周内进行庭审
be set in the next two weeks.
反对  法官大人  她已经准备好几周了
Objection, Your Honor, she's had weeks to--
鱼与熊掌不可兼得  斯佩克特先生
You can't have it both ways, Mr. Specter.
你不能既想要证据又想要更多时间准备
You can't demand discovery and ask for more time.
庭审在两周后开始
Trial starts in two weeks.
杰西卡  我们有个问题
Jessica, we have a problem.
谢谢你能指出来  杰克
Thanks for pointing that out, Jack.
我都没发现呢
I had no idea.
我指的不是庭审
I'm not talking about the trial.
是这个
I'm talking about this.
那是什么玩意儿
What the hell is that?
《华尔街日报》的一篇评论文章
An op-ed in the Journal.
"在圣光普照的大地上绝不可能发生的事
"There is no way on God's green earth
就是皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特律所的
"that at least one of the three name partners
三个冠名合伙人中
"at Pearson Specter Litt
没有一个知道自己公司内部的勾当"
didn't know what was going on under their own roof."
"圣光普照的大地"  这是谁写的
"God's green earth." Who wrote it?
斯凯登律所的一个合伙人
A partner at Skaaden.
就算他们不写  也会有别人写
If it wasn't them, it would've been someone else,
因为他们闻到了血腥味
because they smell blood.
我才不管他们闻到了什么
I don't care what they smell.
为了这个律所我放弃了一切
I've given up everything for this firm,
如果任何人想从我手中夺走它
and if anybody tries to take it from me,
他们得从我僵硬冰冷的死尸手中掰下来才行
they'll have to pry it from my cold, dead hands.
-那你的计划呢  -你说什么
- And what's your goddamn plan? - Excuse me?
杰西卡  律所的名声正受到质疑
Jessica, our reputation's taking a beating.
我们需要恢复它
We need to rehabilitate it.
也就是要做法律援助  你懂的
That means pro bono, and you know it.
不管一个无偿案件多么有价值
One free case is not going to move the needle,
它都不会改变现状
no matter how worthy it is.
我指的不是单个案件
I'm not talking about one case.
我指的是为我们的客户最在意的慈善机构
I'm talking about a series of cases
提供一系列无偿服务
for our clients' most valued charities.
这最好不是你的新阴谋  杰克
Oh, this better not be another scheme, Jack.
你觉得这是我的一步阴谋
You think this is a move?
不然你认为我会怎么想
Now why would I ever think that after you tried
你刚想方设法从我手中夺权没多久呢
to take my firm from me six times in the last ten minutes?
我确实想夺权上位
I did try to take over from you.
但我这辈子都效力于这个律所
But I've been at this firm my entire career,
而现在我在为它抗争
and I am fighting for it now.
-你认为我没有为它抗争吗  -我确定你有
- And you think I'm not? - I'm sure you are.
但我之所以会拿着这份对律所的控告
But you're also the reason I'm holding this indictment
你也是首要原因
of our firm in the first place,
因为这上面说的很对
because what they're saying is true.
你敢告诉我
And don't you dare try to tell me
你不知道迈克・罗斯的事吗
you didn't know about Mike Ross,
你我都清楚你一直都知道的
because we both know you did.
你到底想干什么
What the hell do you want?
既然你都让我大老远跑来一趟了
Oh, since you made me come all the way down here,
我觉得我就不雇专人了
I thought I'd save the taxpayers some money
好给纳税人省点钱
on hiring a server.
雇专人干什么
A server for what?
请你未婚妻  我想问她几个问题
For your fiancée. I'd like to ask her some questions.
哪儿凉快哪儿待着去
Get the hell out of here.
想送传票  你自己给她
You want to serve a subpoena, you serve it to her.
那样的话  我就看不到你现在的表情了
Well, then I wouldn't get to see the look on your face.
你真以为我不知道你的要害吗
Did you really think I wouldn't hit you where it hurts?
我只是把最弱的那点留到最后而已
I was saving your weakest spot for last.
祝你们愉快  先生们
Have a nice day, gentlemen.
怎么了
What?
知道吗
You know what.
该给那个女人点颜色看看了
It's time we give that woman a taste of her own medicine.
你什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
我们雇一个外所律师
It means we hire a lawyer from an outside firm,
查查她关心的事情
and we dig up dirt on someone she cares about.
-你疯了吧  -你看到她是怎么对唐娜的了
- Are you out of your mind? - You saw what she did to Donna.
她用同样卑鄙的手段对瑞秋
It's only a matter of time before she tries
-只是时间的问题  -迈克
- to pull the same shit with Rachel. - Mike--
哈维  是你教的我
Harvey, you're the one that taught me that
当有人向你施压时  要以牙还牙
when someone puts pressure on you, you put it back on them.
我还教过你  如果想要反击
I also taught you if you're gonna take a swing at someone,
你最好能一击制胜
you better knock them out,
如果我们照你说的做
and if we pull the shit that you're talking about
然后被抓了
and get caught,
最终下场就是我被踢出这个案子
all that happens is I get thrown off this case,
然后一切玩完了
and it's game over.
哈维  我不能眼睁睁地看着
Harvey, I can't stand by and watch while the people
我在乎的人受到攻击  你也不能
I care about get attacked, and neither could you.
迈克  我向你保证
Mike, I promise you,
无论如何我都会为瑞秋挺身而出
I will be there for Rachel every step of the way.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我需要你好好过一遍那些箱子里的文件
I need you going through every one of those boxes.
因为如果那个女人真准备好了上庭
Because if that woman is ready to go to trial,
那她掌握到的证据就肯定不止
she's got a lot more than an e-mail
路易女友的一封邮件
from Louis' girlfriend.
诉讼双雄
第五季第十三集
-瑞秋・赞恩  -是我
- Rachel Zane. - Yes?
安妮塔・吉布斯  我是
My name is Anita Gibbs. I'm the--
我知道你是谁
Yes, I know who you are.
你亲自来找我  真是荣幸
I'm flattered you came for me personally.
但我们这三天不能见面
But we aren't supposed to talk for another three days,
现在我律师也不在  所以
and I don't have my lawyer with me, so--
这并非正式询问
This isn't a formal interrogation.
没必要律师陪同
That won't be necessary.
那我告诉你什么有必要
Then I'll tell you what is necessary.
你得白纸黑字的写一份证明表示我所说的
You're going to put in writing that anything I say to you
任何话都无效
is inadmissible.
我就知道你会这么说  所以准备了这个
I suspected you'd say that, which is why i prepared this.
如果你想向一个真从法律学校毕业的人咨询
I understand if you'd prefer to ask somebody who's actually
这份文件是否具有法律效力  我可以理解
completed law school if that's legally binding.
我完全有能力判断
I'm perfectly capable of determining
这是否有法律效力
if this is legally binding or not.
而且我也绝不会让你
And I'm not going to let you
骗我跟你讲任何事
bait me into saying anything to you.
我不介意
Well, that's fine with me.
我不是指望你说什么
I'm not looking for you to talk.
是希望你听听我的话
I'm looking for you to listen.
正式通知
Well, it's official.
不管案子结果如何
No matter what happens at trial,
律所也不会比迈克・罗斯活得久了
this firm isn't surviving Mike Ross.
我知道那篇社论了  路易
I know about the editorial, Louis.
什么社论
What editorial?
我说的是夏季新律师申请的事
I'm talking about the summer associate applications.
-有多可怕  -就三个人
- How bad is it? - Three people.
还不是随便三个人  是三个
Not just any three people, the three people
根本就不配进哈佛的人
that never should've made it to harvard in the first place.
该死的
Goddamn it.
希拉是把垫底的送来了
Sheila's sending us the bottom of the barrel.
她是把给垫底的垫底的人
She's giving us the sludge that grows
送来了
at the bottom of the barrel.
那么
Then...
我认为也许我们该把眼光放在哈佛以外了
I think it might be time to start looking beyond Harvard.
是吗  真是好主意  那不如
Yeah, that's a great idea. You know what?
我们以后有什么就招什么吧
We should start shitting in the urinals while we're at it.
我又没说是亚利桑那州立大学  路易
I'm not talking about the University of Arizona, Louis.
我指的是哥伦比亚  耶鲁  斯坦福
I'm talking about Columbia, Yale, Stanford--
我指的是我们的形象
And I'm talking about appearances.
我们打破规矩突然从哈佛以外招人的话
We break our rule and suddenly hire outside of Harvard--
我们收了哥伦比亚的瑞秋就已经破了规矩
We already broke our rule for Rachel with Columbia.
拜托  这是两码事  你自己也知道
Please, that was different, and you know it.
不  那就是因为迈克
No. It was because of Mike,
所以这才根本就是一码事
which makes it the same goddamn thing.
不管怎样  我们都要让律所运转下去
One way or another, we are going to keep this firm going.
所以你要不想去哈佛以外招人
So if you don't wanna go outside of harvard to do that,
那我建议你赶紧去剑桥
then I suggest you go up to Cambridge,
说服希拉给我们介绍些
and convince Sheila to start feeding us
有资格的申请者
some worthy goddamn applicants.
好了  你先是派车来接我
Okay. So first you pick me up,
又带我来了我最喜欢的咖啡店
then you bring me to my favorite café.
有什么办法  我的调查工作就是做得好
What can I say? I do my homework.
我也不赖  吉布斯女士  所以我不会
As do I, Ms. Gibbs, which is why I'm not falling for you
上你假装示好的当的
pretending to be my friend.
你说得对  我不是你的朋友
You're right. I'm not your friend.
但我愿意动用点影响力
But I am willing to pull some strings
帮你爱的男人进哥伦比亚法学院
to get the man you love into Columbia Law School.
如果你以为我会相信你这个童话
And if you think that I'm gonna buy that fairy tale,
那你的影响力作用的唯一一个人就是我
the only strings you're trying to pull are mine.
这件事里唯一的童话是你以为
The only fairy tale here is the one where you believe
你能毫发无损的度过这一劫
you get out of this thing unscathed.
行了  我跟你谈够了
Okay. We're done here.
瑞秋  我只是想让你清楚你都有哪些路
Rachel, I'm just trying to give you your options.
我知道我的路
I know my options.
那你就该知道你没有配偶特权
Then you know you have no spousal privilege,
也就是说你有义务说出真相
which means you're going to have to tell the truth,
让你未婚夫进监狱
and put your fiancée away.
否则你只能引用第五修正案
Or you're gonna have to plead the Fifth.
或者我可以说他就没干这件事
Or I can say that he didn't do this.
做伪证和引用第五修正案没区别
Perjuring yourself is the same as taking the Fifth,
你的未来一样是毁了
as far as your future is concerned.
你这是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
我的意思是你总有一天
I'm saying that someday you're going to face
要面对律界的性格健康委员会
the character and fitness committee of the bar,
我真的很怀疑他们会认可
and I seriously doubt they're going to admit somebody
干过这种事的人
who did that.
你是在恐吓证人吗
Are you trying to intimidate a witness?
没错  有天我会面对委员会的审查
Because yes, someday I will face that committee,
但明天他们得先听听你的事
but tomorrow they're going to be hearing about you.
我是你度过此劫的唯一活路
I'm your only way out of this mess.
把真正该付责任的人交给我
Just give me the people who are actually responsible for it,
我会确保你和迈克的余生都能继续
and I'll see to it that both you and Mike can practice law
在法律界谋生
for the rest of your lives.
求你告诉我这是最后一箱了
Please tell me that's the last one.
没错
It is.
除了另一间会议室堆的一百个之外
Except for the hundred in the other conference room.
-天哪  -是啊
- Holy shit. - Yeah.
庭审策略第一招
Trial strategy 101.
把对方埋进资料堆
Bury the other side in paperwork,
这样他们就不知道自己在找什么了
so they can't find what they're looking for.
那我们在找什么
And what are we looking for?
吉布斯的庭审策略
Gibbs' trial strategy.
这些盒子里藏着
Somewhere in these boxes are the pieces
她拼起来立案的拼图碎片
that she is putting together to make her case.
找到它们  就能确切知道我们要对付什么了
We find them, we know specifically what we have to fight.
那些碎片确切可能长什么样
And what specifically might those things look like?
证人名单  面谈  关于罗拉・詹森的一切
Witness lists, interviews, anything to do with Lola Jensen,
我本该在哈佛时期间的对账单
utility bills from when I was supposed to be at Harvard--
等等  慢点
Wait, wait, wait. Slow down.
-你抄着些干什么  -免得忘了
- Why are you writing this down? - So I can remember it.
而且我们也需要建立个系统
And because we need a system.
而且还因为你从没做过文献整理
And because you've never done doc review before.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
你是怎么做到做了这么久的法律秘书
How you've been a legal secretary this long,
-还从没做过文献整理  -那我告诉你
- and never have done doc review. - I will tell you how.
因为我是你见过的最会读懂人心
Because I'm the best damn person you've ever seen
最会预测需求
at reading people, anticipating needs,
基本上能处理所有事的人
and generally dominating everything.
也就是说这件事上
So, in this situation,
你完全帮不上忙
you're going to be absolutely no help at all.
-毫无办法  -我去找瑞秋
- None whatsoever. - I'm getting Rachel.
那是什么
What's that?
你看像什么
What does it look like?
像我没时间处理的东西
It looks like something I don't have time for.
那就挤点时间出来
Well, make time.
杰西卡  我们有一千箱垃圾要过一遍
Jessica, we've got a thousand boxes of shit to go through,
-而且开庭就剩两周了  -什么
- and I've got trial in two weeks. - What?
没错  时间已经定了
That's right. The date's been set.
所以抱歉我现在没法陪你吃甜甜圈
So I'm sorry that I can't have a doughnut with you right now,
但我现在有稍比那重要点的事要做
but I've got something a little more important to deal with.
哈维  我理解  但我们客户被盯上了
Harvey, I understand, but our clients are being circled.
我们的名誉在受损
Our reputation's getting tanked,
新律师应聘人也都差得不行
and we're getting sent shit associates.
可迈克・罗斯面临着牢狱之灾
And Mike Ross is facing prison.
你只负责一件事
And you're handling one thing,
而我要负责其它所有事
while I'm handling everything else.
-杰西卡  -算了  别介意  哈维
- Jessica-- - No, never mind, Harvey.
我明白你其实不在乎
It's clear that you really don't care
这家律所是否分崩离析
about keeping this firm together.
我为了让律所不分裂都辞职了
I resigned to keep this firm together.
但这好像没有奏效啊
Well, it sure doesn't seem to be working out that way,
不是吗
does it?
好的  我会让秘书在周一安排一次会面
Great, I'll have my secretary set up a meeting for monday.
如果那是关于你那破公益诉讼的
If that meeting's about your pro bono bullshit,
-取消掉  -什么
- cancel it. - What?
你自己说过的  杰克
You said it yourself, Jack.
其它律所已经闻到血腥味了
Other firms smell blood.
友善不会让鲨鱼退却
Well, you don't get a shark to back off by playing nice,
你得用棍棒打在他脸上让他退却
You do it by clubbing him in the face.
他们挖我们的客户  我们也挖他们的
They come after our clients, we go after theirs.
《华尔街日报》写报道的
Clients aren't the ones writing editorials
可不是客户  杰克
for "The Wall Street Journal", Jack.
你要挖个律师
You want to poach an attorney.
我要挖整个部门
I wanna poach a whole goddamn department.
这可是完全不同的一个选择啊
That is definitely another way to go.
这是我们仅有的选择
It's the only way to go,
因为如果我们没有做那些我们说没做过的事
because if we didn't do what we're saying we didn't do,
-我们就会这么行动  -我明白了
-this is what we do. - I get it.
你要告诉外界我们是清白的
You're trying to convince the world we're innocent.
杰克  我不关心我的敌人是否认为
Jack, I don't give a shit if my enemies think
我是无辜的
I'm innocent or not.
我只关心他们是否认为自己能击败我
I give a shit whether they think they can take me down,
这就是为什么我不去忙着做公益诉讼
which is why I'm not going to cower in some pro bono corner,
来向他们表现自己的友善
trying to convince them that I'm friendly.
我要主动出击
I'm going to kick some ass,
让他们重温我的凶猛
and remind them that I'm fierce.
你在这里啊  我到处找你
There you are. I've been looking everywhere for you.
瑞秋  我们需要你的帮助  你跑到哪里去了
Rachel, we need your help. Where have you been?
跟安妮塔・吉布斯在一起
With Anita Gibbs.
什么  你怎么能跟她会面
What? How did you let that happen?
她在街上守着我  拿着一份文件
Because she ambushed me on the street,
声明我们俩的谈话
with a document that said our conversation
不会作为证据
would be inadmissible.
她这么做就是
And if she did that is because
为了套你的话
she didn't want to talk to you,
她想给你下套
she wanted to get in your head.
迈克  我知道她打算干什么
Mike, I know what she wanted to do.
她怎么说的
What did she say?
她说她能让你上哥伦比亚大学
She said that she could get you into Columbia,
在这一切平息之后你可以成为一名律师
and that you could be a lawyer after all this is over.
瑞秋  她在撒谎
Rachel, she's lying--
你觉得我看不出来吗
You think I don't know that?
我们已经讨论过了
Well, we've already been over this.
只有我们背叛了哈维和杰西卡之后
The only way she is gonna help us is if we help her
她才会帮我们
put Harvey and Jessica away.
迈克  这个我知道  但是我们没有讨论过
Yes, Mike, I know that, but we didn't go over the part
我因为拒绝作证而无法当律师的事
where I don't get into the bar because I took the Fifth.
我的天哪
Oh, goddamn it!
这就是为什么我希望哈维在场
This is exactly why I wanted Harvey to be there.
-她果然套住你了  -她没有影响到我
- She got into your head. - She didn't got into my head.
她把我们的梦想吊在那里诱惑我
She dangled our dream in front of me,
我知道这个我们不能拿
and I know that we can't have that.
但这并不意味着我不能掌控局面
It doesn't mean I can't handle this.
看情形你好像并没有掌控局面
It doesn't seem like you're handling it.
-我有掌控  -你哭了
- I am. - You're crying.
不  我释放我的情绪是因为我承认它的存在
No. I'm releasing my emotions so that I can persevere
而不是否认它进而失去理智
instead of denying them and losing my mind.
我今天不能失去理智
Which I can't do today,
因为我跟院长有个会面
because I have a meeting with the Dean.
我独自藏在这里
Now, I came in here to be alone
是为了处理这些烂事
so I can deal with my shit,
所以你不介意的话  让我一个人待会儿
so if you don't mind, I would like to be alone
让我自己处理这些
so I can deal with my shit.
你搜寻到什么结果了没有
Hey, did you find something in the discovery?
当然有
Yeah, sure as hell did.
我发现吉布斯跟瑞秋见面了
I just discovered that Gibbs picked up Rachel.
什么  吉布斯逮捕她了吗
What? She arrested her?
没有  她拿份破文件在路边等着她
No, she pulled up to the curb with some document.
我不关心她拿了什么狗屁文件
I don't give a shit what she pulled up with.
瑞秋应该明白不要跟她接触
Rachel should know not to go with her.
是啊  她的律师应该告知她这个
Yeah, and that would've been an excellent thing
可她的律师不在场
for her lawyer to tell her, except her lawyer wasn't there.
-什么  -你向我保证过
- Excuse me? - You promised me
法律程序的每一步都会陪着她
that you would be with her every step of the way.
我保证过我在取证的时候会跟她在一起
I promised I'd represent her at a deposition,
不是全天24小时做她的保姆
not babysit her 24 hours a day.
也许与其生瑞秋的气
Maybe instead of getting mad at Rachel,
我们应该想想怎么对付吉布斯
it is time for us to figure out how to go after Gibbs.【轴】
-又来这个  -对  又是这个
- This again. - Yes, this again.
我跟你说过她会找上瑞秋的  现在她找上了
I told you she was gonna go after Rachel, and now she has.
我也告诉过你如果你打算对付谁
And I told you if you're gonna go after someone,
你最好直接把他踢出局
you better knock them out.
那你最好找到一个把吉布斯踢出局的方法
Then you better figure out a way to knock Gibbs out soon,
因为如果你不做  我去做
because if you don't, I will.
路易
Louis.
-你在这里干什么  -怎么了
- What are you doing here? - What?
你觉得你可以当着我的面撒谎然后就完了
You thought you could lie to my face and get away with it?
-我从来没有对你撒谎  -真的吗
- I never lied to you. - Really?
因为你发誓你不会
Because you swore
站出来承认那封邮件
you wouldn't come forward about that e-mail,
但是你食言了
but you did.
现在你又给我这么几个新人提名
And you you're pulling this associate shit.
我没有主动站出来  是他们找到我的
I didn't come forward. They found me.
而且新人的事也不是我搞的
And I'm not pulling any associate shit.
那你怎么解释这份
Then what do you call this pathetic excuse
悲催的候选人名单
of a candidates list?
我觉得这是自然而然的
I call it inevitable.
因为我们的学生识字
Because our students can read.
-那篇报道  -是的
- The editorial. - Yes.
那篇报道
The editorial.
所以不是你把那些渣子给我们
So you're not sending us sludge.
路易  我没有做什么
Louis, I'm not doing anything.
你们律所正在被
Your firm is being investigated
联邦检察官办公室调查
by the U.S. Attorney's office.
没有人会把自己的职业生涯搭进一个
And no one is going to risk their career on a place
不到一个月就要倒闭的地方
that may not even exist in a month.
他们会的  如果你去说服他们
They might, if you convince them to.
-路易  我不能那么做  -希拉  求求你
- Louis, I can't do that. - Sheila, please.
我之前来过一次  恳求得到第二次机会
I came here once before, hoping for a second chance
你并没有给我
and you wouldn't give it to me.
那跟这事有什么关系
What does that have to do with this?
因为如果当时我们在一起了
Because if we'd gotten back together then,
我就不会在这家律所了  但我还在那里
I wouldn't even be at the firm now, but I am.
那是我的所有了
And it's all I have.
我能理解你不给我第二次机会
I understand you not giving me a second chance then.
但现在我再次恳求你
But I'm begging you...
给我的律所一次机会
Give my firm one now.
路易  就算我愿意帮你也没用
Louis, even if I wanted to, it won't work.
-你怎么知道没用  -我就是知道
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
因为他们会问我去皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特工作
Because they're going to ask me if I think it's a good idea
是否明智  而我知道答案是否定的
For them to work at Pearson Specter Litt, and I don't.
-希拉  -路易
- Sheila-- - Louis.
请不要让我对他们撒谎
Please don't ask me to lie to them.
你要干嘛
What are you doing?
我想着你你是不是要在这里待一整天
I'm just wondering if you're gonna stay in here
一直看这些材料
going over stuff all day.
那我还能干什么  去看球赛吗
What else would I be doing? Going to the ball game?
我不清楚啊  哈维
I don't know, Harvey,
我以为你会在想办法让安妮塔・吉布斯
I thought maybe you'd be doing something to get Anita Gibbs
放过瑞秋
to back off Rachel.
唐娜  她威胁说要去找律师协会
Donna, she threatened to go to the bar.
那简直是胡扯  没有瑞秋的证词
It's a bullshit hypothetical that she couldn't do
她是不能这么做的
until after Rachel testified.
瑞秋的证词得在庭审后才有
Which is after the trial starts,
这才是我现在正准备的事情
and that's what I'm goddamn working on.
哈维  我只是想说
Harvey, all I'm saying is
迈克为事情着急的时候
that when Mike gets worked up about something,
不一定能做出最好的决定
he doesn't tend to make the best decisions.
如果他不为调查证据做准备的话
Well, if he doesn't work on the discovery,
他就要去蹲监狱了  所以
he's gonna go to jail, so...
-你让我怎么办  -我不知道  哈维
- What do you want me to do? - I don't know, Harvey.
但你至少得去找安妮塔・吉布斯谈谈
But you better at least go talk to Anita Gibbs,
因为迈克已经明确告诉过你了
because Mike gave you a warning loud and clear.
如果你不行动的话  他来
If you don't do something, he will.
杰克  我一般不出来喝咖啡
Jack, I don't often come outside for my coffee,
但是我出来了就说明我觉得我有需要
but when I do is because I'm feeling the need
一个人静静
for a little alone time.
我出来是因为我知道你不想让
Well, I came out here because I knew you wouldn't want
任何人听到我接下来要说的话
anyone hearing what I have to say.
你是来告诉我你能搞定的吗
Are you here to tell me you can get the job done?
不  我来是告诉你如果你想让我把事情搞定的话
No, I'm here to tell you if you want me to get it done,
那就要破费了
you're going to have to open your wallet.
我不会多付你钱
I'm not paying you more money,
就为了让你挖个墙脚
just to get you to poach a department.
我说的不是我
I'm not talking about me.
我说的是贝克・豪斯特勒律所的房地产部门
I'm talking the Real Estate Division of Baker Hostetler.
-他们想要多少  -现在的两倍
- How much do they want? - Double what they're making.
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
杜威・巴兰坦就是这么被拖垮的
That's what broke Dewey Ballantine.
你不能同时有两班合伙人
You can't have two classes of partners.
那我们就不能挖部门了
Then we can't poach a department,
因为考虑到目前的状况
because they're the only ones even willing to come here,
他们是唯一愿意来的
considering what's going on.
那就开条件吧
Then make the offer.
让我安安静静地喝完我的咖啡
And let me have my goddamn coffee in peace.
斯科特女士
Ms. Scott,
有位哈维・斯佩克特先生找你
there's a Harvey Specter here to see you.
他说有急事
He says it's urgent.
让他进来
Send him in.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
为了进来说自己是哈维  你胆子还真不小啊
You have some balls pretending to be Harvey to get in here.
你是叫过我"小哈维"来着
Well, you did call me "Baby Harvey" once.
我才不管以前叫过你什么
I don't give a shit what I called you.
-出去  马上  -斯科特  斯科特  求你
- Get out! Now! - Scottie, Scottie, please.
听着  我知道你肯定不会见我的
Listen, I knew you would never agree to see me,
但我得跟你谈谈
and I need to talk to you.
谈什么
About what?
我需要有人来对付
I need someone to bring an action
-安妮塔・吉布斯的妹妹  -你疯了吗
- against Anita Gibbs' sister. - Are you insane?
听我说  她不光是冲着我来的
Listen to me. She's not just coming after me.
-现在连我的未婚妻也不放过  -我不在乎
- She's coming after my fiancée. - I don't care.
如果我真帮了你  还不如给那女人打个电话
If I do that, I might as well call the woman up,
直接告诉她你那一通狗屁里有我一份功劳
and tell her that I'm in on your whole bullshit too.
-那就从你的律所里挑个人  -更不用说
- We get someone from your firm-- - Not to mention
我跟哈维说了
I told Harvey that I never
我连你的名字都不想再听到
even wanted to hear your name again.
他没告诉你  是吧
He didn't tell you about that, did he?
那我猜他也没变
Well, I guess he hasn't changed,
因为他也没有告诉我你的事
because he didn't tell me about you
直到一切都为时已晚
until it was too late either.
所以你未婚妻的事我很遗憾
So I am sorry about your fiancée,
但现在请你出去
but I need you to go now.
斯科特  这女人不得到她想要的东西
Scottie, this woman is not gonna stop
是不会停的
until she gets what she wants.
而她想要的  正是哈维
And what she wants is Harvey.
所以我不是求你为了我和瑞秋
So I'm not asking you to do this for me and Rachel.
而是求你为了他
I'm asking you to do it for him.
你成人礼的请柬吗
Is that an invitation to your bar mitzvah?
我那天可没空
Because I'm busy that day.
是一封因你不正当接触证人
It's a motion to have you sanctioned
而对你申请制裁的动议
for improperly contacting a witness.
我可没有非正当联系任何人
I didn't improperly contact anyone.
胡说
Oh, bullshit.
你和瑞秋・赞恩单独见面
You got Rachel Zane alone so you could
就是为了劝她告发我
offer her a deal to turn on me.
可那并没有什么不对啊
And there's nothing wrong with that.
你听我说
You listen to me.
这件事一开始你就一直在
You've been pulling shit like this
像这样搞小动作
from the second this thing started.
先是不让我的客户见他的律师
You denied my client access to his attorney,
然后又针对唐娜进行虚假指控
you fabricated charges against Donna,
现在又来干扰证人
and now you're tampering with a witness.
干扰证人对我的案子有百害而无一利
And all witness tampering would do is hurt my own case,
圣光普照  我究竟为什么要这么做
and why on god's green earth would I do that?
你刚说什么
Why did you just say?
我说你真是疯了才会觉得
I said you're insane if you think that--
不是  你刚说"圣光普照"
No, you said, "On god's green earth,"
跟那篇文章里用词一模一样
which is exactly what that editorial said.
我记得是因为我当时还想
I remember because I thought,
"哪个80岁以下的人用这种词啊"
"What person under 80 uses that phrase?"
看来我找到她了
Well, looks like I found her.
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你当然知道  因为整件事都是你一手策划的
You sure as hell do, because you planted that goddamn thing.
有证据吗
You have any proof?
你没有
No, you don't.
就算真的是我一手策划的
But even if I did plant that,
那也肯定是因为
it would only have been
你们不可能不知道
because there's no way that one of you
到底发生了什么事
did not know what was going on.
除非你们中有人承认
And until one of you admits that,
不然我就会一点一点整垮你们的律所
I'm going to take apart your firm brick by brick.
你要是真想递交那动议  随你
So you want to file that thing? You go ahead.
这根本就阻止不了我
It's not going to stop me for one second.
赫里克院长
瑞秋  请
Rachel, please.
-请坐  -谢谢院长
- Have a seat. - Thank you, Dean.
我得说我真的很期待
I have to say I've so been looking forward
我的第一次学生回访
to my first student review.
自你的第一次面试起
And ever since your first interview here,
你就给我留下了很深的印象
you've done nothing but impress me.
这也正是为什么提出这件事我非常遗憾
Which is why I'm sorry to have to bring this up now.
提出什么
Bring what up?
你这次的法学院入学考试分数比之前的
The fact that your last LSAT score was significantly higher
要高出很多
than your previous ones.
那是因为我这次
That is because I studied
学习得超级努力啊
incredibly hard the last time.
是你努力学习
Did you study hard?
还是你的未婚夫替你努力学习了
Or did your fiancée study hard for you?
你觉得入学考试是迈克替我考的
You think Mike took the LSAT for me?
我觉得他还得被控
I think he's been indicted
比这更严重的罪名
for more serious crimes than that.
况且还有指控说
And now there are allegations
他有过替考法学院入学考试的前科
that he's taken the LSATs for people.
真是难以置信  那考试是我自己考的
I can't believe this. I took that test myself.
但我有责任保护
And I have a responsibility to protect
这所大学的声誉
the reputation of this university.
那你要怎么做
And how exactly are you proposing
来保护这所谓的声誉
to protect that reputation?
开除任何危及本校名誉的人
By expelling any dangers to it.
当然了  除非  由于某些原因
Unless, of course, for some reason
这些针对他的指控被撤销了
these allegations against him are dropped.
安妮塔・吉布斯找你了  是不是
Anita Gibbs called you, didn't she?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我不过是出于礼貌告诉你
I'm simply giving you the courtesy of letting you know
假如我得在你的前程和本校的未来间做出选择
that if I have to choose between your future  and this university's,
我不会选你
I'm not choosing you.
那么拜托  告诉吉布斯女士
Well, then, please, tell Ms. Gibbs
谢谢她的礼貌之举
thank you for the courtesy.
斯科特  你在这里干什么
Scottie, what are you doing here?
我简直不敢相信你派他来找我
I can't believe you sent him to me.
-派谁  -别和我玩那套
- Sent who? - Oh, don't give me that.
上次你来找我
The last time you came to me,
你说是因为迈克让你来的
you said it was because Mike made you.
这一次  就是你让他来的
Well, this time, you made him.
我没让他干任何事
I didn't made him do anything.
那么你把他教得不错  因为他来找我
Well, then, you taught him well, because he came to me
和我玩攻心战
and pulled on my heart strings
以便让我帮你做事
to get me to do something for you,
但这一次  我拒绝
but this time the answer is no.
我不会去对付安妮塔・吉布斯的
I am not going after Anita Gibbs.
斯科特  我绝不对让你去做这种事的
Scottie, I would never ask you to do something like that.
那就有趣了  因为你曾让我放弃一个案子
That's funny, because you asked me to throw a case
以保护迈克不被抓
to keep Mike from getting caught.
放弃一个案子是不会让你成为靶子的
Throwing a case doesn't put a target on your back.
假如你真的不想让我成为靶子
If you really wanted to keep a target off my back,
你一开始就不会告诉我迈克的事
you never would've told me about Mike in the first place.
斯科特  我没让他那么做
Scottie, I didn't tell him to do that.
那我猜你俩之间的问题和我们当初的一样
Well, then, I guess you two are having the same problem we did.
你们互相不沟通
You don't talk to each other.
但既然你弃我选他  那这事就和我无关了
Since you chose him over me it's not my problem anymore.
我没有弃你选他
I didn't chose him over you.
不  你有
Yes, you did.
而且无论你承不承认
And whether you choose to admit it or not,
当初就是迈克的秘密害我们分手的
it was Mike's secret that broke us up in the first place.
你没和我说一声就让她进来了
You let her in here without telling me?
我当时在会议室  翻看调查证据
I was in the conference room, going over discovery.
你打算做什么
What are you going to do?
我不知道我要做什么  但无论做什么
I don't know what I'm gonna do, but whatever it is,
我都打算立刻动手
I'm gonna do it right now.
哈维  冷静点
Harvey, calm down.
我才不打算冷静呢
I'm not gonna calm down,
你让我去对付吉布斯
you told me to go after Gibbs
以防止迈克做出什么傻事  我去了
to stop Mike from doing something stupid, and I did,
但一切就像我说的  都是浪费时间
and all that did was waste our time like I said it would.
哈维  吉布斯在攻击瑞秋
Harvey. Gibbs is attacking Rachel,
他爱的女人
the woman he loves.
所有人中你最应该能理解那一点
You of all people should be able to understand that.
我才不管
I don't give a shit.
他无权去找我爱的人的麻烦
He had no right to go after someone I love.
好吧  你知道吗  哈维
Okay, you know what, Harvey?
要受审的是迈克  不是斯科特
Mike is the one on trial here, not Scottie.
而他所做的不过是求她办些事
And all he did was ask her to do something.
所以也许你真正生气的是
So maybe the thing that you're really upset about
她说得没错
is that she was right.
怎么样了
Well, how did it go?
我们认识很久了  杰克
We've known each other a long time, Jack,
我也真的很想帮忙
and I'd really like to help,
但我帮不了
but it's not gonna happen.
你说过假如我能让他们出的钱翻倍...
You said if I could get them double--
我说的是至少得翻倍我才好开口去问
I said it would take at least double just to get me to ask.
我问了  然后他们笑得让我待不下去
I did, and they laughed me out of the room.
假如我能搞来更多钱呢
What if I could get you more?
无论花多少钱都无法让他们
There's no number that's going to get them
投向皮尔逊-斯佩克特
to come to Pearson Specter
因为他们不相信这家律所能存活下去
because they don't believe there's gonna be a firm to come to.
那你为何还要约我来这里见面
Then why did you ask to meet me here?
因为在我向他们提过你的提议之后
Because after I asked them about your offer,
我还问了他们我的提议
I asked them about mine.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我告诉他们我有一个前兄弟会兄弟
I told them a former fraternity brother of mine,
他恰好是一名也许想另寻良机的厉害律师
who happens to be a kick-ass lawyer might be looking for a change.
你在给我提供一份工作吗
You're offering me a job?
杰克  皮尔逊-斯佩克特日是艘下沉的船
Jack, Pearson Specter's a sinking ship.
我们是进了些水
We've taken on some water.
你们那是进了一海洋的水
You've taken on an ocean.
你到底是为什么想留在那里
Why the hell would you wanna stay there?
我会告诉你为什么的
I'll tell you why.
因为假如那艘船沉了
Because if that ship sinks,
我会再找到一份工作
I'll find myself another job.
但假如它没沉
But if it doesn't,
我就有机会成为船长之一了
I have the chance to be one of the captains.
假如我现在就投奔你
If I come to you now,
我一辈子就只能干这个了
I'll never be more than a lifer.
作为我的朋友  告诉我我错了
As my friend, tell me I'm wrong.
你没错
You're not wrong.
别告诉我他们为我们也特别印了一份晚报
Don't tell me they printed out a special evening edition on us too.
还没
Not yet.
我读了
I read it,
顺带一提
by the way,
在飞去波士顿的路上
on the flight up to Boston.
你有被那篇文章气到吗
And did it fire you up?
快给气死了
Pissed me the hell off.
你没搞定希拉  是不是
You couldn't get it done with Sheila, could you?
杰西卡  那张单子上的候选人不是她选的
Jessica, she didn't send us the candidates on that list.
而是只有他们三个提交了申请
They were the only three that even asked to be submitted,
就因为那张报纸上的屁话
and it was because of bullshit like that.
-大家都不敢来这里了  -的确
- People are scared to come here. - They are.
我试图说服希拉安抚他们  但我失败了
I tried to get Sheila to make them unafraid, but I couldn't.
没关系
That's all right.
没关系的  路易  这不是你的错
It's all right, Louis. It's not your fault.
一旦迈克的事泄露出去
Once word got out about Mike
这种事注定会发生
this was bound to happen.
从雇用迈克这件事上我学到了一点
What I learned from hiring Mike
那就是并非所有的好律师都上过哈佛
was that not all great lawyers went to Harvard.
你的意思是
What are you saying?
我联系了斯坦福  耶鲁
I contacted Stanford, Yale,
哥伦比亚  宾大  以及其他所有...
Columbia, Penn, and all the rest...
前20的法学院
top 20 law schools.
我正式打开了皮尔逊-斯佩克特-利特的大门
I officially opened up the doors to Pearson Specter Litt.
我知道你有多不情愿这么做  路易
I know how much you hated to do that, Louis,
但有时我们不得不去做一些事...
but sometimes we need to do what we have to...
为了生存
to survive.
-我还能做些别的什么吗  -没有了
- Is there anything else I can do? - No, there isn't.
现如今  我们只需要挺过这场庭审
Right now, we just need to get through this trial,
并向上帝祈祷哈维能帮
and pray to god that Harvey gets
迈克・熊孩子・罗斯脱罪
Mike goddamn Ross off the hook.
你在洗碟子
You're doing dishes.
所以呢
So?
你讨厌洗碟子
So you hate doing dishes,
这意味着出问题了
which means something's wrong.
没什么问题
Nothing's wrong.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我都不知道自己该不该说
I don't even know if I should say it,
因为上次我说了之后你暴跳如雷
because the last time I did you got so mad.
你以为我要离开你
You thought I was gonna leave you.
你说你想让我向你倾诉
And you say you want me to share things with you,
但我不确定你是不是真心的
but I don't know if you do,
因为当我倾诉了
because when I do
你就也变得特别沮丧  让我...
you seem to get so upset that I--
我懂了  你想说做交易的事
I get it. You want to talk about making a deal.
我不知道我要做什么
I don't know what I wanna do.
我只是...
I just--
她说她能把你弄进哥伦比亚大学
She said that she could get you into Columbia,
而你说得很对
and you're right.
这话说到我心里了
It got into my head.
瑞秋  之前她就这么说了
Rachel, we've been over this.
那是在撒谎
She was lying.
那是在我知道她能指使院长之前
That was before I knew she was able to get to the dean.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
今天我和院长见面了
I had my meeting with him today,
我原本以为他要和我说
And I thought he was going to tell me
我做得有多好  可结果...
how well I've been doing, and instead...
他威胁说要开除我
He threatened to expel me.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  但这并不意味着这是吉布斯干的
Okay, that--that doesn't mean that it was Gibbs.
-你不在那里  -我是不在那里  好吧
- You weren't there. - No, I wasn't there, all right?
但没跟吉布斯沟通过得情况下
But it's not crazy to assume that they would question
就来问你是否认识我也是合理的事
whether or not you knew about me without talking to Gibbs.
那没跟吉布斯沟通过得情况下
Is it crazy for them to mention a crime
他们提到一项你没被指控的罪名算不算合理
you haven't even been accused of without talking to Gibbs?
-什么  -他们说有流言称
- What? - They said there are rumors
你替别人考法学院入学考试
of you taking the LSATs for people
他们说是你替我考试
And they're accusing you of doing that for me.
起码现在我知道该怎么做了
Well...At least now I know what I need to do.
哈维
Harvey.
我知道该怎么阻止吉布斯向瑞秋施压了
I know how we can stop Gibbs from pressuring Rachel.
包括不跟我说一声就跑到斯科特那里吗
Does it involve going to Scottie without telling me?
-哈维  -该死  你无权这么做
- Harvey. - Goddamn it, you had no right.
我当然有这个权力
I had every right,
因为我知道吉布斯会不断越界
because I knew Gibss would keep crossing lines,
而她之前就是这么做的
and that's exactly what she did.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
她让哥伦比亚大学的院长
She manipulated the dean of Columbia
威胁瑞秋说要开除她
into threatening to expel Rachel.
证据呢
Where's your proof?
他们跟她说是我替她考的法学院入学考试
They accused her of having me take the LSATs for her,
唯一的问题在于  没有任何记录
and the only problem is, there's no record of me
显示我被控那么做过
ever having being accused of that.
是你在法庭上见到的那个人
The guy you saw in court.
没错  他叫大卫・格林
Yes, his name is David Green.
他肯定和吉布斯说过这事
He must've told Gibbs about me,
于是她利用这点
and then she used that
来让院长威胁瑞秋
to get the dean to strong-arm Rachel.
这是在滥用权力
That's abuse of power.
我跟你说过  这个说法唯一的问题在于
I told you, the only problem with that theory is,
只要大卫・格林跟吉布斯说起这事
David Green tells Gibbs about you,
他的事业就完了
and his career is done.
那他肯定是向她匿名举报的
Then he must've told her anonymously.
那也帮不了我们  因为我们还是没有
Which doesn't help us, 'cause we still don't have
她联系过院长的证据
any proof that she contacted the dean.
是没有  但我要找出证据并不难
No, we don't, but it wouldn't be that hard for me to get.
不行  这可能是陷阱  风险太大了
No, it could be a setup. It's too risky.
这整件事的风险都很大
This whole goddamn thing is too risky,
可现在瑞秋的前途危在旦夕
but right now Rachel's future is in jeopardy,
为了她就算多判我几年
And if I have to risk tacking on a few years to save her,
都算不了什么
is not even a close call.
好吧  尽管去做吧
All right. Do what you have to do.
别被抓就行
Just don't get caught.
你敲门了
You're knocking.
这说明如果不是有坏消息就是你别有所求
That means it's either bad news or you want something.
-我搞不定那个部门  -我猜猜
- I couldn't get the department. - Don't tell me.
他们说我们已经没有能挖人的地位了
They said we're in no position to poach anybody.
在给我一份工作之前
That's exactly what they said,
他们就是这么说的
right before they offered me a job.
所以你是来跟我说你接受了吗
So you're here to tell me you took it.
我是来问你想要我接受吗
I'm here to ask you if you want me to take it.
我想不想能有什么区别
What the hell difference does it make what I want?
杰西卡  当我离开波士顿时  别人说我是叛徒
Jessica, when I left Boston, people said I was a traitor
说我觉得我的才华在家乡得不到施展
and that I thought I was too good for my own hometown.
事实并非如此
Well, it wasn't true.
而我明白真正的考验
But I knew the real test for me
并不是在家乡大展身手
wasn't making it in my own hometown.
而是在这座环境最艰险的城市
It was making it in the toughest city
开创事业  就我所知
in the world, and as far as I'm concerned,
我还没做到
I haven't done that yet.
你想成为冠名合伙人
You want to be made name partner.
我想知道你愿不愿意考虑
I wanna know if it'll ever even be on the table.
现在我就能给你肯定的答案
I could say yes to that right now,
可你怎么知道你能相信我
but how would you know you could trust me?
我别无选择
I have no other choice.
我又怎么知道自己能相信你
And how do I know I can trust you?
-这是什么  -你知道是什么
- What's this? - You know what it is.
这是丹尼尔・哈德曼手里关于你的把柄
It's what Daniel Hardman has on you.
现在你也有了
Now you have it too.
大卫・格林
David Green.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
看来你确实记得我
So you do remember me.
当然记得
Of course I do.
你是我们正在起诉的人
You're the guy we're prosecuting.
那个冒牌律师
The fake lawyer.
我的能耐可不止如此  你懂的
Oh, I'm more than that and you know it.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
你当年雇我是因为我够聪明
You hired me because I'm smart.
可你不知道的是我有过目不忘的能力
What you don't know is that I have a photographic memory,
这意味着我七年前就记住了
which means I have your drivers license number
你的驾驶证号
from seven years ago memorized.
这也算不上什么  因为我有复印件了
Not that it matters, because I also made a copy.
我把所有客户的驾照都复印下来了
Like I made a copy of all my clients' licenses.
那也证明不了什么
That doesn't prove anything.
或许吧  可我同样记得那104个问题
Maybe not, but I also remember every answer I put down
我是如何作答的
on a 104 question test.
如果那都不算证据  世上就没证据了
If that's not proof, I don't know what is.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我想要是安妮塔・吉布斯让哥伦比亚大学的院长
I want proof that Anita Gibbs' pressuring the dean of Columbia
开除瑞秋・赞恩的证据
to expel Rachel Zane.
-我没法这么做  -你可以的
- I can't do that. - Yes, you can.
好吧  他们在法学院是同学
Okay, they went to law school together.
这就是他们的联系
There's your connection.
公共记录这种旁证可没什么用
Circumstantial public record not good enough.
如果被人抓到我帮了你
I do what you're asking and get caught,
那我就没法呆在联邦检察官办公室
and my career at the U.S. Attorney's office is over.
如果我向地方检察官检举此事
I give what I have to the D.A.,
你就连做律师的资格都没了
and your career as a lawyer is over.
这样做只会连累你自己
If you do that, you only implicate yourself.
是啊  可能你还没注意到  混账
Yeah, maybe you didn't notice, asshole,
我已经被审了  如今你们却找
but I'm already on trial, and now you're coming
我爱的女人的麻烦
after the woman I love.
事实就是你不配做律师
And the truth is you don't deserve to practice law.
我或许也不配  但她配
Maybe I don't either, but she does.
相信我  当事关这件事时
And, believe me, when it comes to this,
我才不管你我死活
I really don't give a shit about me or you.
如果我找不到你想要的东西怎么办
And what if I can't find what you're looking for?
这么说吧  大卫
You know what, David?
你或许还没聪明到能在法学院入学考试拿178分
You might not have been smart enough to get 178 on the LSATs,
但我很确定你不会蠢到那事都干不了
but I'm pretty damn sure you're smart enough to do that.
-这是什么  -你要签的东西
- What's this? - That's what you're gonna sign.
上面写了你们要撤销一项
This says you're dropping a charge
对我诬告的诉讼  以交换
of malicious prosecution in exchange for
我承认进行了不当侵权
me admitting a sanctionable offense.
并且放弃传唤瑞秋・赞恩
And for backing the hell off going after Rachel Zane.
-这是开玩笑吗  -不
- Is this a joke? - No.
让哥伦比亚法学院院长来给你做脏事
And neither is getting the Dean of Columbia Law
也不是开玩笑的
to do your dirty work.
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你很清楚
You know exactly what we're talking about.
除非你想让我们告诉全世界
And unless you want us to tell the world
你勾结法学院老朋友
that you intimidated a witness
恐吓证人
by colluding with your old law school buddy,
你就得签了那个
you're going to sign that.
你们没有任何证据
You don't have a shred of proof
证明我让任何人做了任何事
that I had anyone do anything.
我有一份给你的匿名举报的副本
I have a copy of an anonymous tip sent to you,
说我代人考法学院入学考试
saying I took the LSAT for people,
还有一段十分钟后从你办公室打给
and a record of a phone call from your office
哥大院长的电话的录音
to the Dean of Columbia ten minutes later.
那什么也不能证明
That's no proof of anything.
那证据足够我们
It's proof enough for us to sue Dean Herrick
把赫里克院长告到陪尽所有财产了
for every penny he's ever made.
你觉得等我们把他送上证人席
You think when we get him in a deposition
他不会开口吗
he isn't gonna crack?
你们觉得你们很聪明是吗
You think you're pretty smart, don't you?
够赢个联邦检察官了
Smart enough to outwit a U.S. Attorney.
如果我们在这儿能赢你  你凭什么觉得
And if we can do it here, what makes you think
我们没法在法庭上赢呢
we won't be able to do it in court?
因为法庭跟这些废话无关
Because court is not about bullshit like this.
那里要讲事实
It's about facts.
事实是  你不是律师
And the fact is, you're not a goddamn lawyer.
你把事情解决了
You have it done.
-你怎么知道的  -因为你
- How'd you know? - Because you're doing
把胸挺得很高
that puffy chest thing you do
你每次自我感觉特别良好时都那样
when you feel really good about yourself.
我不挺胸的
I do not do a puffy chest thing.
你会的  别紧张
Yes, you do. And relax,
因为我爱你  也爱你的胸
because I love you and your chest.
我也爱你  和你的胸
Well, I love you and your chest.
那句错了
Oh, that came out wrong.
真的  我是想说你的头脑
Seriously, I meant your mind.
你聪慧的法律头脑
Your brilliant legal mind.
如果不是你和你聪慧的法律头脑
Well, if it wasn't for you and your brilliant legal mind,
我现在也不会在法学院里
I might not be in law school right now.
不  我理解他们很多人都已经申请...
No, I-I understand that a lot of them already--
好  如果有人想要
Okay, well, if anyone wants to--
不  我明白  我明白
No, I see. I see.
也许明年吧
Maybe next year.
再见
Bye.
路易
Louis.
我得跟你聊一聊
I need to talk to you for a second.
又是什么事
What now?
杰克・索罗夫想知道
Jack Soloff wants to know
我们会不会有天考虑让他做命名合伙人
if we'll someday consider making him name partner.
我们为什么要那么做
Why the hell would we do that?
因为我让他去挖墙脚
Because I sent him to poach a department
结果对方给了他份工作邀请
and instead they offered him a job.
我明白了
I get it.
没人想来  所以你的办法就是
Nobody wants to come here, so your answer
给我们屋檐下的敌人
is to give our in-house enemy
他梦寐以求的升职
the promotion he's always wanted.
路易  以前是你最想让我这么做
Louis, you're the one who wanted me to do it before.
但你劝住了我
And you talked me out of it.
因为你是对的
Because you were right.
就像你以前总是对的
Just like you used to be right about everything.
可现在你好像总是做错事
But now it seems like you're wrong about everything.
你这话什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
我刚接到那20所学校里最后一所的消息
I just heard back from the last of those 20 schools.
结果是他们跟哈佛的意见一致性
And it turns out they have a lot more in common
比我们想得要强多了  因为他们
with Harvard that we thought, because none of them
都不想跟我们扯上关系
wants to do anything to do with us
因为我们的领导糟透了
because our leadership sucks.
小心你的语气  路易
You watch yourself, Louis.
我不用小心
I don't need to watch myself.
我需要在你屁股底下点把火
I need to light a fire under your ass.
因为我们的未来要溜走了
because our future is slipping away,
而给杰克命名合伙人地位
and offering Jack name partner
或是跟上帝祈祷哈维
or praying to god that Harvey
能把迈克的案子摆平
just gets Mike off the hook
都没法阻止这事发生
isn't going to stop it from happening.
好  路易
Okay, Louis.
你想做点祈祷之外的事
You want to do something more than pray,
哈维在想办法给迈克脱罪
Harvey gets Mike acquitted,
你现在就滚去哈佛
then you get your ass back up to Harvard
确保希拉不会出现在庭审上
and you make sure Sheila doesn't show up to that trial.
唐娜
Hi, Donna.
有...
Is there, um...
有什么我能帮忙的吗
Is there something I can help you with?
我只是想说我很遗憾
I just wanted to say that I'm sorry
为院长那件事
about what happened with the dean.
我很高兴迈克解决掉它了
And I'm glad that Mike took care of it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很抱歉...
I'm sorry that...
我在整个过程中都没来看你
that I didn't come to you with this whole thing,
但我...
But I-I...
他们在给你施压  要你背叛哈维
They were pressuring you to turn on Harvey
而以我们上次对话情况看
and based on our last conversation,
你不认为我是讨论那事的合适人选
you didn't think I was the right person to talk to about that.
一如既往地  你是对的
As usual, you're right.
瑞秋  我生气是因为我不愿去想
Rachel, I got upset because I didn't want to think
我必须在哈维和我爸爸间做选择时
about what I do if I have to choose
会怎么做
between my dad and Harvey.
因为这整个情况都糟透了
Because this whole situation sucks.
我们可能得做很艰难的选择
And we may have to make hard choices,
而我想告诉你无论你做什么
and I want you to know that no matter what you do,
你是我的朋友
you're my friend.
我会永远爱你
And I will always love you.
我也会永远爱你
I will always love you too.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
我来只是因为我不希望你
I only came here because I don't want you
或迈克・罗斯或者这律所的任何人
or Mike Ross or anyone else from this firm
再出现在我的律所
showing up at my firm ever again.
所以要我帮你做什么
So what can I do for you?
我在想你说的
I was thinking about what you said
我不会跟自己承认真相的话
about me not admitting things to myself
而我想聊聊
and I wanted to talk to you about it.
为什么
Why?
我想让你知道真相
I wanted you to know the truth.
真相又是什么
And what exactly is the truth?
我们分手不是因为迈克
Our relationship didn't end because of Mike.
而是因为我没有准备好
It ended because I wasn't ready to confront
面对自己的问题
what was wrong with me,
我不知道我是否能准备好  但...
and I don't know if I'll ever be ready, but...
我在见心理医生  我希望告诉你这事
I've been seeing someone, and I wanted to tell you about it.
我知不知道有什么价值呢
And why does it matter that I know that?
因为如果我能安然渡过这件事
Because if I ever get out of this in one piece,
我想知道能不能再联系你
I want to know if is okay to call you again.
哈维  你永远都可以联系我
Harvey, it's always okay to call me.
我自己其实也在见心理医生
I've actually been going to therapy myself,
我也不知道整件事结束后
and I don't know where I'll be
我会走到哪一步
when this whole thing is over.
但我非常希望你能安然渡过
But I do hope that you get out of this thing in one piece.
打扰下
Excuse me.
抱歉  我...
Hi, excuse me. I, uh--
我不确定您是不是认识我
I'm not sure if you know who I am--
我在这里工作过两个月  瑞秋
I worked here for two months, Rachel.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
我只是  想说我知道
I just--I wanted to say that I know
你被扯进了这场较量
that you got caught in the crossfire.
我知道那种感觉
And I know how that feels.
我想说我很抱歉
And I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
-谢谢你  -没关系
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
瑞秋
Rachel.
你有想过这一切结束后会怎么样吗
Have you thought about what may happen when this is all over?
你是说如果迈克进了监狱
You mean if Mike goes to jail.
我是说就算他没进
I mean even if he doesn't.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
就算他被判无罪  也有很大可能
Even if he is acquitted, there is an excellent chance
被撤销执照
he will be thrown out of the bar
永远无法执业
and never be able to practice law again.
那不重要  因为迈克已经准备好
It wouldn't matter, because Mike is prepared
永远不再执业了
to never practice law again anyway.
有时人觉得自己准备好了
And sometimes people think they're prepared
但其实他们没有
and they're not.
我不懂
I don't understand.
瑞秋  迈克得看着你去做
Rachel, Mike is going to have to watch you do
他梦想的工作
what he dreams of doing,
如果他跟哈维有一点相像的话
and if he's anything like Harvey,
他可能会觉得他能比你做得好
he probably thinks he can do it better than you.
那就有可能
And there is a possibility
他会为此怨恨你
that he might resent you for it.
我感谢你的建议
I appreciate the advise.
但迈克不是那样的人
But Mike is not like that.
那我很抱歉我说话过界了
Then I'm sorry I overstepped my bounds.
路易
Louis.
你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here?
我们已经谈过了
We've been over this.
我没什么可做的
There's nothing I can do--
我不是为了新律师来的
I'm not here about the associates.
我需要你收下这个
I need you to take this.
-那是什么  -这是去阿根廷的机票
- What's that? - It's a ticket to Argentina.
我需要你去那儿待到审判结束
I need you to go there until the trial is over.
我为什么要那么做
And why would I do that?
因为你在那儿  传票就没效力了
Because the prosecution has no power to subpoena you there.
我来说清楚  你想让我逃出国去
Let me get this straight. You want me to flee the country,
好让你保住你自己
so you can protect yourself.
我想让你逃出国去  保护你自己
I want you to flee the country so you can protect yourself.
-路易  -希拉  你去出庭作证
- Louis-- - Sheila, you take that stand,
就会说出伤害我们的话
and you're gonna say things that hurt us,
就意味着哈维会说伤害你的话
which means Harvey is going to say things that hurt you
而我没法承受那个
and I will not be able to handle that.
事实不会伤害我  路易
The truth isn't gonna hurt me, Louis.
赛斯女士  当你声名
Isn't it true, Ms. Sazs, that while you claim
没人能在未授权状态下进入哈佛档案室
no one had unauthorized access to the Harvard file room,
你是否犯了失职之错
there were times you were derelict in your duties?
我一生从未失职
I've never been derelict in my life.
那怎么解释就在庭上
Then how does that explain the fact that there's a man
就有一名未被授权
in this courtroom that had unauthorized access
却曾进入的人呢
to that very room?
-路易  拜托  -是因为你跟那人
- Louis, please. - Was it because you had
有过一段感情吗
a relationship with that man?
一段最终未能成正果的感情
A relationship that ultimately failed?
-那跟...  -案情无关吗
- That's not-- - relevant?
关系大了
It's more than goddamn relevant!
因为他跟你分手时
Because when he broke up with you,
你开始散布这恶毒的流言来攻击他
you started this vicious rumor to get back at him.
那是谎话  都是谎言
That's a lie. Those are all lies.
你跟他发生性关系
It is a lie that you had sex with that man,
还把他一个人留在
and left him alone in the supposedly
本应不许进入的哈佛档案室  也是谎言吗
impenetrable Harvard file room?
路易  这会让我丢掉工作
Louis, this could cost me my job.
该死  哈维根本不在乎
Goddamn it! Harvey is not gonna care.
不
No.
那不是谎话
It's not a lie.
如果你让他进去了
And if you did that with him...
我们为什么要相信
why should we believe
你不会让别人进去
you didn't do that with others?
对不起
I'm sorry.
希拉  我只是想保护你
Sheila, I'm only trying to protect you.
如果你真想保护我
If you really wanted to protect me,
就不会告诉哈维这些事
you wouldn't tell Harvey those things in the first place.
他会希望我告诉他
He's gonna want me to tell him.
任何我知道的能帮上他忙的事
Anything I know that would help.
你让我不要逼你说谎
You asked me to not make you lie.
那求你  不要逼我对他说谎
Please, don't ask me to lie to him.
好  路易
Okay, louis.
我走
I'll go.
你还在这里干什么
What are you still doing here?
我们还有个审判呢
We've still got a trial coming up.
我要做好全面的辩护准备
I'm gonna make any headway on my defense,
我得走了
I need to get going.
你要辩护
Your defense?
是的
Yes.
我来辩护
My defense.
你是在说我觉得你在说的话吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
因为对这事一直有个评价
Because there's an expression about that.
就是"你要那么想  那你就是蠢货"
It says, "If you're thinking it, you're a fool."
你听到了  她说
You heard her. She said,
"事实就是我不是律师"
"The fact is that I'm not a goddamn lawyer."
那唯一改变那个事实的办法就是
Well, the only way to change that fact is for a jury
让陪审团看到我是个律师
to see me being a goddamn lawyer.
你要那么做  他们看到的就只是
You try that, all they're gonna see
该进监狱的某人
is someone going to prison.
那是胡话  我能搞定她
That's bullshit. I can handle her.
你都没参与过
You've never even gone through
刑事审判
a criminal trial before.
是的  那你上次参与是什么时候
Oh, yeah, and when was the last time you did?
几年前了
How many years ago was it?
难以置信  你觉得你能比我强
I don't believe it. You think you're better than me?
跟谁强没关系
This isn't about who's better.
重点是谁对这案子更有利
It's about who's better for this case.
是我命悬一线
And my life is on the line.
如果我因为自己的行为栽了  那我认栽
If I go down because of my call, I can take it.
如果是你让我栽了  我没法认
If I go down because of yours, I can't.
这不光是你的命  是我们所有人的
This isn't just your life. This is all of ours.
那就像我说的
Well, like I said,
这是我的决定  我要做
it's my call and I'm making it.
抱歉打扰你们
I'm sorry to interrupt.
这事还没完
This isn't over.
我刚看了一遍调查证据
I just finished going through discovery
我们有麻烦了
and we have a problem.
什么麻烦
What is it?
他们找到了特雷弗
They found Trevor.